Richard R. Neill Coursework Collection MC.163
New York University Archives
Richard R. Neill Coursework Collection
1949-1952
New York University Archives
Neill, Richard R.
MC.163
0.5 Linear Feet
The collection consists of the coursework of Richard R. Neill, a New York City-born graduate of NYU, who attended the English program in the Graduate School of Arts and Sciences between 1949 and 1952. Materials in the collection include syllabi, notebooks, term papers, and exams.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged in chronological order, with the exceptions of a notebook from English 126.
Biography of Richard Neill
Richard R. Neill was born in New York City on June 20, 1925. He graduated from Princeton with an A.B. in English in 1938 and enlisted in the U.S. Navy in 1943. After the end of World War II, Neill attended NYU for his graduate education from 1949-1952, earning an M.A. in English in 1953. Neill joined Prentice-Hall Publishers as an editor and worked there for the duration of his professional life, retiring in 1985 as President of Executive Reports (P-H business publishing subsidiary).
Other Finding Aids
A 2002 paper finding aid is available.
Provenance
A part of the collection, spanning 1949-1951, was acquired from Richard R. Neill in 2002. Files from 1952 were transferred in the same year from Princeton University's Seeley G. Mudd Manuscript Library.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of syllabi, notebooks, term papers, and exams of Richard R. Neill compiled while he attended NYU's Graduate School of Arts and Sciences from 1949 to 1952 to earn an M.A. in English.
Access Restrictions
Institutional records of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation (the date on which each document was written). Board of Trustees records are similarly closed for 35 years from the date of creation. The opening date for files spanning several years will be 20 years from the most recent date. Access will be given to material already 20 years old contained within a collection that is not yet open when such material can be isolated from the rest of the collection.
Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files with information that falls under the University's Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) policy are permanently restricted.
Please contact the University Archivists with specific questions regarding restrictions.
American literature -- 20th century.; English literature |x Study and teaching.; Schlauch, Margaret, 1898-1986; Gibson, William; Johnson, Samuel; Fisher, John; Cargill, Oscar, 1898-1972; New York University -- History
- Materials for Course - English 291-292: American Literature Since 1900 (Professor Oscar Cargill), 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Materials for Course - English 291-292: American Literature Since 1900 (Professor Oscar Cargill), 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Materials for Course - English 216: Canterbury Tales (Professor Margaret Schlauch), 1950 Spring (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Materials for Course - English 216: Canterbury Tales (Professor Margaret Schlauch), 1950 Spring (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Materials for Course - English 201-202: The Developement of Modern English (Professor John Fisher), 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Materials for Course - English 201-202: The Developement of Modern English (Professor John Fisher), 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Materials for Course - English 126: Types and Theories of Tragedy (Professor Samuel Johnson), 1951 Spring (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Materials for Course - English 126: Types and Theories of Tragedy (Professor Samuel Johnson), 1951 Spring (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Materials for Course - English 295-296: American Fiction (Professor William Gibson), 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Materials for Course - English 295-296: American Fiction (Professor William Gibson), 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Notebook from English 126, 1951 Spring (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Notebook from English 295-296, 1952 Spring (Box 1, Folder 7)